按说大家挤在这里 应该不可能
You'd think loneliness would be impossible
感到孤独
all crammed in here,
但这列火车的设计就是要分隔我们
but this train was designed to separate us
把我们跟财物隔开 跟亲友隔开
from our possessions, from our loved ones.
现在 我们的一分一毫都对某人有一定价值
Now every last shred of us is worth something to someone.
一切都很稀有
Everything's rare,
所以你得用私人的东西来买
so you gotta pay with something personal.
我们都在换取更好的
And we're all trading up
最有价值的东西
for the most valuable thing there is --
门路
access.
通向头等厢的门路
Access all the way to First,
在那里 为消遣而赌博
where they hold the table for sport,
然后再一点点往下换
then trade it right back down.
人们躲避我
People avoid me
因为我照顾沉睡者
because I care for the Sleepers,
但那是我的价值
but that's my value,
是我打开门路 住进二等厢的办法
how I open doors and live in Second.
我可以换东西
I can trade for things,
而最弱的人只能把他们的碳换成肥料
while the weakest can only trade their carbon for compost.
我们继续推进
So we keep pushing,
射频识别
往前车移动
pushing uptrain,
争取更鲜活的体验
pushing for access to feel more alive.
门路就是自由
Access is freedom.
门路就是力量
Access is power.
我们在雪国列车上为此杀戮
We kill for that on Snowpiercer,
就在这1001列车厢里
1,001 cars long.
雪国列车
第一季 第三集
我们都不知道夜车是什么
We don't even know what the Nightcar is,
在那里他们会逼你做什么
what they'll make you do up there.
什么都比这强
Anything's better than this.
-扎拉 -我会死的
- Zarah. - I'll die.
我受不了了
I can't do it anymore.
这是我的决定
This is my decision.
这我们留了很久了
We held onto these for a long time,
但现在它们作为商品更有价值
but they're worth more as a commodity,
如果你有麻烦了拿去做交易吧
to trade if you get into trouble.
祝你好运 安德烈
Good luck, Andre.
-她来了 -该死的卖身贱人
- Oh, yeah, there she is. - Goddamn sell-out!
去吧
Yeah, go on.
去让有钱人看看车尾人怎么干
Go show those rich men how we do in the tail.
只有四英尺
Four feet away, huh.
-走吧 -恭喜你了
- Walk away! - Good for you.
好了 可以安静下来吗
Alright, can we settle?
请安静下来
Settle down, please.
谢谢
Thank you.
早上好
Good morning.
我们都知道
We all know
这48小时很不容易
it's been a tough 48 hours.
看来威尔福德先生也在考虑这些事
It seems the events have been on Mr. Wilford's mind, as well.
他亲自为我们大家写了张字条
He's written a personal message for us all.
"我忠诚可靠的列车员们
"To my loyal and trusted crew,
你们是此次任务成功的关键
without whom this mission could never succeed,
值此逆境之际
in this time of adversity,
我请求你们 人性的领班们
I ask you, the lead stewards of humanity,
要保持精神和决心的不动摇
to remain unshaken in spirit and resolve,
你们这七年来一直高尚地如此坚持着
as you've done so nobly these past seven years.
靠你们的坚持 我们将挺过此次磨难
By your steady hand, we will ride out this hardship
在冰天雪地里生存下来
and outlive the ice,
我们的事业和需求是我们的基石
bound by our cause and our need.
威尔福德"
Wilford."
温斯顿·丘吉尔
Winston Churchill.
什么
I'm sorry?
"精神和决心的不动摇"
"Unshaken in spirit and resolve."
威尔福德先生用了丘吉尔的名言
Mr. Wilford was paraphrasing Churchill.
我会告诉他你发现了
I'll tell him you noticed.
告诉他骚乱在酝酿中
Tell him there's unrest brewing.
谋杀案 车尾人暴动
The murders. The Tailie uprising.
限粮首先影响了三等厢
Third will feel the brunt of the rationing.
已经有人在讨论罢工
There's already talk of job action.
说到这儿 威尔福德先生建议
To that point, Mr. Wilford suggests we work
维修期间 要努力安抚乘客
to ease the minds of passengers while we do repairs.
露丝 如果我们把下周的搏击赛
Ruth, what if we moved next week's prize fight
改到今晚怎么样
up to tonight?
分散注意力
Distraction.
太聪明了
It's brilliant.
我们安排一场大赛
We make an event of it,
获胜者将从三等厢升级到二等厢
and the winner gets a full upgrade from Third to Second.
这能激发三等厢人的斗志
It's aspirational for Third,
还会提醒一等厢 他们的生活有多美好
and it'll remind First how good they actually have it.
指挥官
Commander...
你能应付搏击赛吗
you can handle the fight?
当然了
Of course.
很好 就这么定了
Good. Settled.
永动机永不停息
The Engine will provide.
放开我
Get off of me!
Get off me, get off me!
吓到你了吗
That frighten you?
这是威尔福德先生的主意
It was Mr. Wilford's idea.
头上套着个袋子
At least with a bag on my head,
我知道威尔福德什么都不想让我看到
I know how much Wilford actually wants me to see.
让我解释清楚
Let me explain clearly.
我们在这里都有我们的位置
We each have our place up here,
我们的道路
our lane.
在你获取威尔福德先生的信任之前
And until you earn Mr. Wilford's trust,
你的道路很窄
your lane is narrow.
你需要关心的就是找出
Your only concern is finding out
谁折磨并杀死了肖恩·怀斯
who tortured and killed Sean Wise.
如果你再试图和车尾交流
And if you try communicating with the Tail again,
我就亲自把你的头从洞里伸出去
I'll stick your head out a port myself.
我能和第一起谋杀案的目击者谈谈吗
Can I have access to the witness of the first murder yet?
不能
No.
她还在昏迷中
She's still unconscious.
好吧
Well...
威尔福德对我的信任足够告诉我
Does Wilford trust me enough to let me know
肖恩·怀斯在监视什么吗
what Sean Wise was informing on?
可以
Yes.
肖恩·怀斯密切关注着黑市
Sean Wise kept tabs on the black market.
他试图找到一种在三等厢肆虐的
He was trying to find the source of a new drug
新型毒品的来源 克洛诺
wreaking havoc in Third -- Kronole.
克洛诺可不是新的
Kronole's not new.
已经在车尾里存在了两次循环了
It's been in the Tail for two revolutions.
你们没分到钱吗
Oh, you're not getting a cut?
独裁国家通常会控制着毒品交易
Authoritarian states usually control their own drug trades.
雪国列车是一艘方舟
Snowpiercer's an ark.
不是独裁国家
It's not an authoritarian state.
行吧
Okay.
如果肖恩·怀斯在找克洛诺
Well, if Sean Wise was looking for Kronole,
我们就从这儿开始查
that's where we start.
你们要做的就是给司闸员口交
All you gotta do is go down on a Brakeman.
你手下小奥在车尾会用克洛诺来交换口交
Your boy Oz trades "K" For blowjobs in the Tail.
看看你 警探
Well, look at you, detective.
已经开始查案了
Already working on the case.
你们应该看看我不戴手铐的样子
You should see me without the handcuffs.
司闸员提尔 你穿着便衣啊
Brakeman Till, you're out of uniform.
不知为何昨晚那个车尾人逃出牢房成了我的错了
Somehow it's my fault the Tailie got out of his cell last night.
-我都没有... -你别说了
- I wasn't even -- - You shut up.
在二等厢肯定特别棒
Must be pretty nice up here in Second,
如果可以在床上躺一天的话
if you can just lie around in bed all day.
你没觉得这有点激励人吗
You don't find it a little aspirational?
一点点吧
Some of it.
妮基含冤被囚
Nikki falsely imprisoned?
在我眼皮底下存在一个食人帮
A cannibal ring right under my nose?
真丢人
It's embarrassing.
现在我连内裤都找不到了
And I can't even find my underwear.
妮基是我们唯一的目击者
Nikki's our only witness.
乘客服务部的那婊子不让人见她
That bitch from Hospitality's blocking access to her.
反正你从妮基嘴里也问不出什么 她还是犯糊涂
Yeah, you won't get much out of Nikki. She's still confused.
她不是还昏迷着吗
I thought she was unconscious.
-最好别去招惹梅兰妮 贝丝 -为什么
- I wouldn't go there, Bess. - Why not?
因为如果梅兰妮这么做 就说明这是威尔福德的意思
Because if Melanie's doing it, it's what Wilford wants.
好吧
Okay, well...
就是这种想法
it's that kind of thinking
让一个无辜女孩进了抽屉
that put an innocent girl in the Drawers.
你不会想和梅兰妮·卡维尔有交集的
You don't want to cross paths with Melanie Cavill.
那我就绕过她
Then I'll go around her.
奥斯维勒
Osweiller.
两面三刀的人渣
Shifty little dodger.
我等不及用这个甩他一脸了
I can't wait to slap him with this.
很好 但等等
Good, but hold up.
现在这个案子陷入了僵局
You're at an impasse with this case.
所以今天 我要狠狠地摇这棵树
So today, I'm shaking the hell out of this tree
一定要摇点东西下来
to make something fall out.
好吧 但列车就像小镇
Okay, the train is like a small town,
大家都会知道你要来了
so everyone's gonna know you're coming.
两年前 你把妮基放进了抽屉
Two years ago, you put Nikki in a Drawer
为了一宗不是她犯的罪
for a crime she didn't commit.
现在你不知道肖恩·怀斯是否
Now you don't know if Sean Wise was murdered
是被同一个疯子所杀
by that same psychopath
还是说另有其人想让
or if it's just somebody else trying to complicate
威尔福德线人的凶案变复杂
the murder of a Wilford informant.
-你想说什么 -我想说
- Your point? - My point is --
这次我主导
I lead this time.
车尾人源源不断向我们涌来
Tailies came pouring out onto us.
我们就用长矛刺那些禽兽
We started sticking pikes in those animals,
-他们很快就屈服了 -小奥
- they buckled quick. - Oz.
听说你是从那儿爬出来的啊
Heard you went crawling out of there on your hands and knees.
还把你的搭档撇下了
And left your partner behind.
-让开 -遵命 长官
- Move it. - Yes, sir.
这是干什么 长官
What's this about, sir?
你在车尾用克洛诺换人给你吹箫
You're trading Kronole for blowjobs in the Tail.
你要信车尾人的话
Gonna listen to a Tailie?
你的供货商是谁
Who's your supplier?
供货商
Supplier?
不 不
No, no.
听着
Look.
我给了车尾一点克洛诺 好吗
I passed a little Kroney to the Tail, okay?
但那来自我们收缴的东西里
But it was just from the stuff that we confiscated,
给了那个胳膊被冻断的女人
for the Tailie woman whose arm they froze off.
这是出于人道
It was a humanitarian act.
你认识肖恩·怀斯吗
Did you know Sean Wise?
-什么 那个死人 -对 那个死人
- What, the dead guy? - Yeah, the dead guy.
怎么了 跟这事有什么关系
W-Why? What's that got to do with it?
我以这趟列车起誓 头儿
I s-- I swear on the train, boss.
别推我脖子行不
Don't push the neck, yeah?
特伦斯 我 我是打算来见你的
Terence, I was -- I was coming to see you --
闭嘴吧你
Oh, shut it.
为什么首席司闸给你施压
Why is the Lead Brakeman leaning on you?
在问克洛诺的事
Was asking about Kroney.
我什么也没说
I didn't say nothing.
那就好
That's good.
那跟他一起的那个车尾警探呢
What about the Tailie detective he's with?
我们 我们让他负责肖恩·怀斯的命案
We, uh -- We pulled him out to work on the Sean Wise murder.
他怎么把命案和克洛诺联系上的
So, how'd he get to Kroney?
他很聪明 我不知道
He's smart. Dunno.
最好不要低估他
I wouldn't underestimate him.
这不用你担心
Don't worry about that.
我们会热烈欢迎那个警察的
We'll give that cop a nice warm welcome.
罗切 听着
Roche. Look, hey.
我告诉过你的
I already told you.
扎拉没有杀害威尔福德的特务
Zarah didn't kill the Wilford rat.
她不是要和他生孩子吗
Well, she was gonna have a baby with him, wasn't she?
听着 他们住一起
Look, she lived with him.
他告诉她什么了
What did he tell her?
你和我的人谈过了
You talked to my guy.
现在轮到我和你的人谈谈了
Now I'm gonna talk to yours.
肖恩生前在农业区工作
Sean worked for Ag-Sec.
他也是个间谍
He was also a spy.
我不知道他和这事有什么牵连
I didn't know he had anything to do with any of this.
-他和你提过克洛诺吗 -没有
- He mention Kronole to you? - No.
那参与制作和分销的人呢
Anybody connected with making it or distributing it?
没有 他对毒品只字未提
No, he didn't mention drugs at all.
他有时候会吹嘘自己认识人
I mean, he bragged sometimes about knowing people
可以给他想要的一切东西
who could get him whatever he needed.
你不是新来的了
You're not new here.
你知道地下黑市是怎么运作的
You know how the underground works.
是谁
Who was it?
管道工
Tunnelmen?
夜车工作人员
Nightcar staff?
还是保洁员
Janitors?
我不知道具体情况
I don't know anything specific.
你也说了他是个间谍 所以他没告诉我们
You're saying he was a spy, so he wasn't sharing it with us.
问好了吗 我还得为搏击之夜做准备
Is that it? 'Cause I gotta get ready for fight night.
-那是什么 -别担心
- What's that? - Don't worry.
你不参加
You won't be attending.
-保洁员 -没事的
- Janitors. - It's okay.
脱吧
Whoo! Off with it!
快走吧 姑娘们
Run along, now, girls.
晚上好
Evening.
搏击之夜
Fight night?
-你可能要输了 -罗伯特最爱搏击了
- Perhaps you lose something. - Robert loves a fight.
是不是 罗伯特
Don't you, Robert?
露丝 我知道你在干什么
Ruth, I see you,
你那些惊喜赌场还有罗马游戏
with your surprise casino and your Roman games.
你只是在掩盖我们会灭绝的真相
You're just misdirecting us from an extinction event.
一对
Snap!
说真的 露丝 我们知道
Seriously, Ruth, we realize
这已不再是一场愉快的旅行了
that this is no longer a pleasure cruise.
但我们的财富造就了这列火车
But our fortunes built this train,
而威尔福德先生正失去控制
and Mr. Wilford is losing control.
资源崩溃
Resources crashing.
车尾暴动
Insurrection in the Tail.
搏击之夜只不过是想转移我们的注意力
Fight Night is nothing but a bald-faced distraction.
没错 但是
Yes, but...
这次会很有趣
it's an entertaining distraction.
请与列车团结一致吧
Please, show some solidarity with the train.
这些人工作辛苦
These people work hard, you know.
仅是看到你们就让他们人心振奋
And it lifts them just to see you.
是啊 妈妈 就当为了三等厢的人
Yeah, Mom, do it for the Thirdies.
一对
Snap!
拜托
Come on!
拜托 爸爸
Come on, Daddy.
拜托 宝贝
Come on, sweetheart.
咱们好好享受今晚吧
Let's make a night of it.
你可以打扮一番
You can get dressed up.
已婚 对吧
Married, right?
20年了
20 years.
有孩子吗
Kids?
真要这样吗
We doing this?
三个孩子
Three kids.
两个没法上车
Two of 'em didn't make it.
艰难的选择
Hard choices.
我们把他们留存心底
We hold them close.
他们是我们前进的动力
They keep us going.
就和扎拉去前列车厢时一样
It was the same thing when Zarah went uptrain.
她曾带给了我温暖
She was my warmth.
番茄汤和一片烤奶酪
Tomato soup and a grilled cheese.
肖恩·怀斯是因为克洛诺的线报遇害的吗
Think Sean Wise got killed on this Kronole tip?
也可能这个威尔福德的特务是被一个连环变态杀人犯
Or did Wilford's rat just get his dick chopped off
割掉了老二
by a serial perv?
你见过威尔福德吗
You ever meet Wilford?
登车前和他握过几次手
Shook his hand a few times before we boarded,
但现在永动机有生物门禁了
but the Engine's bio-secure now.
他让梅兰妮传话
He speaks through Melanie.
不是让你待家里的吗
I told you to stay home.
我有发现
I got something.
原来妮基已经醒了
It turns out Nikki's awake.
好吧 带上莱顿
Okay. Take Layton.
盯着他 我正在吃午饭呢
Keep an eye on him. I'm having my lunch.
我们走
Let's go.
裂缝已经控制住了
I've got the crack under control.
修牲口车厢窗户的博扬队伍进度落后了
Bojan's team is behind on the Cattle Car window.
该死
Oh, shit.
我们不能一直靠这下面供暖
We can't keep pumping heat down here.
主库存量快要到历史最低点了
Main banks are near an all-time low.
前面还要翻越更多的山
And more mountains to come.
-我倒是有个及时方案 -什么
- I can offer one immediate solution. - What?
分离尾车厢
We uncouple the Tail.
我是说把车尾人移到三等厢去
I mean we move the Tailies into Third,
把空车厢分离到侧线以减重
cut the empty weight loose onto a siding.
三等厢会爆发内战的
There'd be civil war in Third.
我需要更可行的方案
I need a more viable solution.
我要是个焊工多好
God, I wish I were welding.
夫人 夫人
Ma'am? Ma'am?
夫人 我...
Ma'am, I...
我是梅兰妮
This is Melanie.
是我
It's me.
怎么了
What's up?
我们不想让调查员看到妮基这个样子 对吗
We don't want the investigators to see Nikki like this, right?
是的 怎么问这个
No. Why?
提尔可能马上就要来了
Till might be on her way soon.
谢谢 珍珠
Thanks, Jinju.
动作快点 她应该是禁止探视的
Make it quick. She's supposed to be off limits.
妮基
Nikki?
妮基 她神志恍惚
Nikki. She's out of it.
这是脱离假死后的正常反应
Oh, that's a common post-suspension reaction.
嗯 她发烧了
Yeah, she's got a fever.
这也是正常现象
That's perfectly normal.
这跟沉睡不同
It's not like sleep.
-什么不同 抽屉吗 -她就是有点昏头转向了
- What's not? The Drawers? - Ah, she's just disoriented.
每个被唤醒的人都会有不同反应
Everyone comes out of it a little differently.
过几天她就会好
She's gonna be fine in a few days.
妮基 你能张开嘴巴吗
Nikki, can you open your mouth for me?
最好别这样
Oh... I wouldn't recommend that.
-天呐 -看着像是克洛诺的戒断症状 对不对
- Oh, Jesus. - Looks a lot like Kronole withdrawal, doesn't it?
不 她只是个长期沉睡者而已
Oh, no, she's just a long-term Sleeper.
妮基 有人给你克洛诺吗
Nikki, has anyone given you Kronole?
-当然没有 -什么克洛诺
- Course not! - What's Kronole?
会让我感觉好受点吗
Will it make me feel better?
她现在不允许探视 医生
She's not cleared for visitors yet, doctor.
我们听说她醒了
We heard she was awake.
那也不代表她准备好接受问询了
That doesn't mean she's ready to be questioned.
请你们离开这里 马上
I'm gonna have to ask you to leave. Now. Now.
请让她休息会儿吧
Please, let's let her rest.
太扯淡了
This is bullshit.
你的假死药是某种形式的克洛诺吗
Is your suspension drug some version of Kronole?
-当然不是 -她的牙龈都黑了
- Of course not. - Her gums are black.
这是很常见的脱离假死后反应
That's a very common post-suspension reaction.
可能跟你说的恰恰相反
Maybe it's the other way around.
也许克洛诺是他们假死药的低级版本
Maybe Kronole's a street version of their suspension drug.
制药原料是受到严格控制的
The materials are tightly controlled.
这不可能 是不是
It's not possible, is it?
克利姆特
Klimpt.
你做了什么
What have you done?
你挪用了假死药物
You skimmed the suspension drug.
然后呢 你把药给了谁
Then what? Who did you give it to?
会有送货员来
Courier comes.
有时候是保洁员
Sometimes it's a janitor.
每一次都是不同的人
Different person each time.
你得到了什么回报
What did you get?
就是些给沉睡者的补给
Just supplies for the Sleepers.
避免产生褥疮的植物软膏
Vegetable balms to prevent bedsores.
威尔福德先生没有想得很周全
Mr. Wilford didn't think of everything.
对不起 对不起
I'm sorry. I-I'm sorry.
我不知道他们用它制造了克洛诺
I-I-I had no idea they made Kronole from it.
能让我们单独谈一会吗
Would you give us a moment, please?
这两个人之间发生了什么
What's going on with these two?
我也想知道
Mm, that's what I want to know.
这东西是什么
What the hell is this?
What the hell is this?!
这是迈尔斯的头发
This is Miles' hair!
-莱顿 -迈尔斯
- Layton. - Miles?
-莱顿 停下来 -迈尔斯
- Layton, stop. - Miles!
-莱顿 停下来 -你们对他做了什么
- Layton, stop! - What did you do to him?!
-停下来 -别这样
- Stop it! - Stop!
这不是你想的那样
It's not what you think.
迈尔斯参加了学徒项目
Miles made the apprenticeship program.
他当学徒了
He made apprentice?
是的
Yes.
他很好
And he's fine.
我们只是给他理了发
We just gave him a haircut.
我要立刻见到他
I want to see him right now.
运动中的物体会保持匀速运动 除非...
Objects in motion stay in motion at the same velocity, unless...
谁知道
Anybody?
制造一个星球
迈尔斯
Miles.
除非物体受到外力的作用
The object is acted on by an external force.
正确
Correct.
谢谢你 迈尔斯
Thank you, Miles.
我有自己的带床帘的床铺 自己的餐叉
I got my own bunk with a curtain, my own fork,
我还讨厌一个东西 叫做蜜桔
and I hate this thing. It's called a tangerine.
听说你在科学课上成绩很棒 小子
Heard you're nailing the science, too, bro.
我所有测试都得满分
I have 100% on all my tests.
是吧 这就对了
See? That's what I'm talking about.
你会成为一名工程师的
You're gonna be an Engineer.
这个我可说不好
I don't know about that.
乔茜会担心我们的
Josie's gonna be worried about us.
是的
Yeah, she is.
你看到学徒项目里的其他孩子了吗
You see any of the other kids from the apprenticeship?
米卡拉在洗衣车里当学徒
Mikala's apprenticing in Laundry.
至于米娅 我不知道
And Mia -- I don't know.
迈尔斯 该吃晚饭了
Miles, it's time for dinner.
你最爱吃晚饭了
Don't you love dinner?
我会时刻注意观察的
I'm keeping my eyes open.
让我下来
Let me down.
那是布兰卡峰
That was Blanca Peak.
有什么问题吗
What's the problem?
我们昨天就应该经过它的
We shoulda passed it yesterday.
我们应该全速行进
We should be running full tilt,
储存能量用来攀登马德雷山
just banking power to climb the Sierra Madres.
昨天的撞击造成了一些严重损害
So, the impact yesterday caused some serious damage.
我们本来就浪费了不少时间
We were already losing time.
发生的事情让情况变得更糟
Whatever happened made it a lot worse.
第四年的减速持续了一个月
The Year-Four Slowdown lasted a month.
一开始是切断灯光 限制用水
Started with darkness, water rations.
问题是 什么时候我们对资源的消耗
Question is, when does our drain on resources
会超过我们作为劳工的价值
outweigh our value as labor?
我认为就在攀登马德雷山之前
Right before the Sierra Madres, I reckon.
-听着 听着 -我们已经晚了一天了
- Look, look, look, look, look, look! - We're a day behind!
威尔福德还没有分离我们
Wilford hasn't uncoupled us yet.
我们只需要稳住阵脚
All we've got to do is hunker down.
同意
Agreed.
双层床 减半用水
Double bunks, half water.
-同意 -同意
- Agreed. - Agreed.
好 让大家朝前走
Alright. Let's pull everyone forward.
减少空间使用以保存暖气
Double up to conserve heat.
-好 -好吗
- Okay. - Alright?
我们在前厢的人会设法帮助我们的
Our people uptrain will help us, somehow.
谢谢你让我见他
Thank you for letting me see him.
但愿现在我们能专注于我们接下来的计划
Well, hopefully now we can focus on our next steps.
梅兰妮
Melanie.
我得见乔茜 他的车尾妈妈
I have to see Josie, his Tail-mom.
我说服她让他走的
I convinced her to let him go.
我知道她很担心他
I know she's worried sick about him.
提尔下次过去的时候可以帮你转告她
Till can give her a message next time she's down there.
听着 她真的需要亲耳听我告诉她他没事
Look, she really needs to hear from me that he is okay.
你确认出了肖恩·怀斯的凶手
How about when you ID Sean Wise's killer,
我就让你见她
I'll let you see her.
再说已经来不及到后面去了
It's too late to get downtrain, anyway.
搏击赛就在今晚
The Fights are tonight.
我刚正在想这事
Yeah, I was just thinking that.
搏击之夜
Fight Night.
感觉那里很容易能找到保洁员
Feels like a pretty good place to find a Janitor.
嗯 但如果他们在卖克洛诺
Yeah, but if they're slinging Kronole,
他们可不会坐下
they're not exactly gonna sit down
跟列车警探谈话
and have a chat with the Train Detective.
这事你就交给列车警探吧
How about we leave that to the Train Detective?
你要照应他 司闸员
Watch his back, Brakeman.
董事会成员 你们都知道
Members of the board, as you well know...
你们都知道 我不喜欢演讲
...as you well know, I am not one for speeches.
不喜欢演讲 但我们
...one for speeches. But we've been --
在第四季度财政里超额收益后
After exceeding earnings in the fourth-quarter financials,
可以说我们经历了一段颠簸的路
it's safe to say that we've been through a bumpy patch.
我不喜欢演讲
I'm not one for speeches,
但我们经历了一段颠簸的路
but we've been through a bumpy patch.
我的顾问告诉我
And my advisers tell me --
所以我想跟你们说
So, I want to say this to you.
全体乘客请注意
Attention all passengers.
鉴于正在进行的工程维修
Due to ongoing engineering repairs,
二等厢和三等厢的人
Second and Third Class
可能会面临电力供应减少
may experience diminished electrical supply.
威尔福德工业的全体人员谢谢你的耐心
All of us at Wilford Industries thank you for your patience.
好
Okay.
头等厢 在那上面
First Class. It's up there.
我押得力助手一张狐皮
Hey! One fox fur on Right Hand Man!
其中一个参赛者是保洁员
One of the fighters is a Janitor.
穿白衣服的就是他们
That's them in white.
但我也不清楚谁是谁
But I don't really know who's who over there.
不是我负责的区域
It's not my beat.
乘客们晚上好
Good evening, passengers.
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
欢迎来到搏击之夜
welcome to Fight Night.
她无处不在 对吗
Kinda everywhere, isn't she?
今晚获胜者的奖励是
The prize tonight, for the victor --
升级到二等厢
a coveted upgrade to Second Class.
但在我们开始前
But before we begin,
我很荣幸宣布威尔福德先生本人
it is my honor to announce that Mr. Wilford himself
想说几句话
would like to say a few words.
谢谢
Thanks.
乘客们晚上好
Good evening, passengers.
你们都知道 我不喜欢演讲
As you well know, I'm not one for speeches,
但我们经历了一段颠簸的路
but we've been through a bumpy patch.
所以我想跟你们说
So I want to say this to you.
要说轨道教会了我什么的话
If the track has taught me anything,
就是不管经历怎样陡的上坡 也终要下行
it's that even the steepest climbs give way to descent.
我会继续做我最擅长的事
I'll keep doing what I do best.
我会照管我们的永动机
I will keep our Engine Eternal.
你们也继续做你们最擅长的事
And you keep doing what you do best --
幸存 幸存 幸存
survive, survive, survive.
幸存 幸存
Survive! Survive!
永动机永不停息
The Engine will provide!
借着这句话 让搏击开始吧
And on that note, let the fight begin.
在那后面
Right back there.
扎拉在吧台工作
Zarah's working behind the bar.
好的
Alright.
你跟在我后面 她是绝不会跟我说话的
She's never gonna talk to me with you attached to my hip.
我了解这女人 好吗
I know this woman, okay?
我要是一个人去的话 可以获得更多信息
We're gonna get a lot more information out of her if I go alone.
那你去吧
Alright, go.
你盯着那些人
Hey, keep an eye on those guys, alright?
确保无人离开
Make sure none of them leave.
你也小心
And watch your back.
他在那
There he is.
列车警探
The Train Detective.
希望那是他的卧底造型
I hope that's his undercover look.
真高兴你没事
I'm so glad you're still okay.
这些保洁员是什么人
Who are these Janitors?
那边留着胡子的是特伦斯
The guy with the beard over there is Terence,
给肖恩提供克洛诺的人
Sean's Kronole connection.
追着他别放 上啊
Keep chasing him! Go, go!
他是首席保洁员 跟他打交道要小心
He's Head Janitor. Watch yourself with him.
我只想打个招呼
I just wanna say hello.
我可以问问他愿不愿意见你
I can ask if he'll meet with you.
你有多想见他
How bad do you need this?
这是第一个关键点
It's the first key.
跟特伦斯打交道总是要付出代价
Well, there's always a price with Terence.
我的结婚戒指
My wedding ring.
我离开车尾那天你给我的
You gave it to me the day I left the Tail.
我把我的拿去交易了 但是留下了你的
I traded mine, but I kept yours.
现在还给你
So, you can have it back now
你若需要的话也可以拿去交易
so you can trade it if you need to.
我最近在想你说的话
I've been thinking about what you said,
关于让我留下来陪你
about staying up here with you.
我仍然爱你 扎拉
I still love you, Zarah.
-但是 -我知道 安德烈
- But -- - I know, Andre.
我知道车尾需要你
I know the Tail needs you.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
你不是保洁员 司闸
You're not a Janitor, Brakeman.
真是惊喜啊
Surprise, surprise.
他们不想见威尔福德的宠物警探
They didn't want to deal with Wilford's pet Detective.
威尔福德派我到这来
Wilford sent me up here
窥探他们的业务
to pry into their business.
我要是特伦斯 我也会想和我谈话
If I was Terence, I'd want to talk to me.
一天两次 我真是逃不掉你了
Twice in one day, I'm stuck dealing with you.
我只需要和特伦斯谈谈
And I need to speak with Terence.
所以你就到这来
So you come here?
你知道他不能冒险见你
You know he can't risk you.
尤其还是个车尾人
A bloody Tailie on top of that.
你只会让他生气
You're just pissing him off.
你出去
So you go out there,
告诉他 也有人盯着我
and you tell him that I got eyes on me, too.
我会甩掉提尔 这样我们就能独处了
I'm gonna lose Till so that we can be alone.
好
Okay.
你觉得我没有你更多的黑料吗 奥斯维勒
You think I don't have more dirt on you, Osweiller?
我和你上司罗切 最近走得很近
Me and your boss, Roche, we getting pretty close.
我说不定可以编造点事
I could probably just make some shit up.
或者让特伦斯再也见不到克洛诺
Or maybe Terence never sees Kronole again.
去告诉他 司闸
Go tell him, Brakeman.
你在疯狂流血
You're bleedin' crazy, man.
靠 妮基
Oh, shit. Nikki?
妮基
Nikki?
右手 双手 上啊
Right hand. Two hands. Gimme something.
加油 蒂娜
Come on, Tina!
你来干什么
What are you doing here?
我需要克洛诺
I need Kronole.
快看 记得那是谁吗
Look, look, look, look. Remember who that is?
她杀了人 她出来干什么
She killed someone. What's she doing out?
她是无辜的
She's innocent.
莱顿先生
Mr. Layton.
你真惹人讨厌
You're a pain in the ass.
来吧
Come on.
-放她下来 -把她放回去
- Put her down! - Put her back!
放开她
Let her go!
这不是大名鼎鼎的车尾警探吗
Well, if it isn't the famous Tailie Detective.
要吃枣子吗
You want a date?
我叫特伦斯
Name's Terence.
别叫我特里
Never Terry.
你来破案
So, you come out to solve a murder,
我的药就断了
and my chemicals dry up.
那玩意是毒药 特伦斯
That shit's poison, Terence.
你该感到羞愧
You should be ashamed of yourself.
你有卖过克洛诺给肖恩·怀斯吗
You ever sell Kronole to Sean Wise?
怎么了
Why?
因为他在上你老婆
Because he was screwing your wife?
不 因为他是威尔福德的线人
No, because he was a Wilford informant.
我没有杀他
Well, I didn't kill him.
别把锅甩给我
Don't put that on me.
不会
No.
你可不想要这样的曝光度
You don't want that kind of publicity.
是的
Yeah.
那么
So...
威尔福德对这个克洛诺问题了解多少
how much does Wilford know about his Kroney problem?
目前为止很少
Very little...yet.
但如果我给他一点关于此次谋杀案的信息
But if I give him something about this murder,
他或许就会忘记整件事
he'll probably forget about the whole thing.
你知道在我做保洁员之前
You know what I was in the Old Time
我在旧世界里做什么工作吗
before I was a Janitor?
保洁员
A janitor.
我给一栋高层建筑做清洁
I cleaned a high-rise building.
我登上这列车 知道我看到了什么吗
I get on this train, and you know what I see?
这列车其实就是栋侧躺着的高层建筑
The train is just a high rise laying on its side.
我知道它是怎么运作的
I know how this thing runs.
而我的大楼成了全世界
And my building just became the whole goddamn world.
有些人生来运气就不好
Some people never had it so good.
仍然在寻找更好的
Well, still looking for better.
三等厢和车尾
Third Class and the Tail,
七成人口
70% of the population.
是的
Yeah.
或许我们可以看到谁在顶层豪华公寓里
Maybe we could see who's in the penthouse.
有梦想是好事
It's nice to dream.
肖恩被杀那晚我有见到他
I saw Sean the night he was killed.
他和另外一个人来买克洛诺
He came down to score "K" With another guy,
我以前没见过那人
no one I'd seen before.
你能描述下吗
Can you describe him?
肯定不是来自这些车厢的
Not from these corridors, no.
或许是头等厢的
First Class, maybe.
30出头 寸头
Early 30s, buzz cut,
保养得好
takes care of himself.
我还需要一样东西 特伦斯
There's one more thing I need, Terence.
一个很小的东西
Something very small.
回家吧 各位
Home you go, people!
边境关闭
The border is closed!
通往三等厢的附属列车出故障了
The subtrain to Third is out of order,
-你们只能走回三等厢 -很成功
- and you're walking home to Third. - It was a great success,
虽然发生了暴乱
despite a riot breaking out.
甚至可能是因为暴乱才成功的
Maybe even because of it.
我会平息暴乱 你去安排他们入睡
Well, I'll put the riot to bed, you put them to bed.
对了 露丝
And, Ruth...
干得漂亮
good job.
能完成威尔福德先生的愿望是我的荣幸
It's an honor just to carry out Mr. Wilford's wishes.
好了
Alright.
边境关闭
The border is closed!
别挤 慢慢来
No pushing. Nice and easy, please.
冷静点
Keep it calm!
-我有一些信息给你 -什么
- I got some information for you. - What?
我们要打烊了
Last call, I'm afraid.
可惜
Shame.
我们正在香谢丽舍大道上跳华尔兹
We were just waltzing down the Champs-Elyees.
-你们真厉害 -嗯
- You're good. - Oh, well,
你或许转移了我们一晚的注意力 梅兰妮
you may have distracted us for one night, Melanie,
但在一两年后
but in a year or two,
当你端上史上最后一盘红酒炖牛肉时
when you serve up history's last boeuf bourguignon...
我不会撒谎
I won't lie.
情况很严重
It's serious.
威尔福德先生可以选择切掉车尾
Mr. Wilford could always cut loose the Tail.
我很高兴你们今晚玩得很开心
I'm glad you had a good evening.
平安回家 LJ
And safe home, LJ.
走吧 亲爱的
Come on, darling.
莱顿获得了肖恩·怀斯被杀之前
Layton has the description of a man
跟他一起的一个男人的外貌描述
who was with Sean Wise just before he was murdered.
-但是 -你让我去车尾见乔茜
- But? - Oh, I'm not gonna tell you
我才会告诉你
till you let me go see Josie in the Tail.
乔茜·维尔斯泰德
Josie Wellstead.
我以为你死了
I thought you were dead.
他们对你做了什么 为什么把你带走
What did they do to you? Why did they pull you out?
我没事
I'm fine.
我没事 听着
I'm fine. Just listen.
我跟迈尔斯说过话了
I talked to Miles.
你会很自豪的
You'd be so proud.
他在上课
He's in a class.
他在学习真正的科学
He's learning real science.
-你看到他了 -他还有进食
- And you saw him? - And he's eating.
三顿饱饭
Three squares.
他有自己的叉子
He's got his own fork.
我看到扎拉了
I saw Zarah.
我完全想错了
I had it all wrong in my head.
这么久以来
This whole time,
我没有看到我眼前的事物
I've not been seeing what was right in front of my eyes.
我很想你 乔茜 我很抱歉
I miss you, Josie, and I am so sorry.
我也是
Me, too.
我也想你
I miss you, too.
够了
That's enough.
他有自己的床
He's got his own bed.
那里还有其他小孩
A-And there's other kids.
他很想你 乔茜
And he misses you, Josie!
我们之间只隔了几扇门
It's only doors between us!
我们要找的人是谁
So, who are we looking for?
你不记得我了 对吗 妮基
You don't remember me, do you, Nikki?
但你知道我是谁
But you do know who I am.